Hi!
If you have a son or daughter or know someone with a physical, mental or even psychological disability, sometimes horseback riding can be really beneficial.
The best way to find out is to actually ask your child's doctor or therapist if they have ever heard of horseback riding therapy.
Also call HIPPA therapy.
What we do here at Hearts Adaptive riding is called therapeutic riding because there is no therapists on staff actually doing therapy.
It is horseback riding for people with disabilities.
It teaches them skills but also they have the benefits of therapeutic riding with physical cognitive and psychological benefits.
But if you know someone with a disability, look up riding.
People with physical disabilities obviously they get a physical workout, they improve their muscle tone, they work on their balance and stability.
People with cognitive disabilities in therapeutic riding can work on numbers, letters, do sequencing, memory.
A lot of things with horseback riding there are two things you are doing at once.
You are steering a horse and kicking them with your legs at the same time.
It brings in a lot of cognitive functions that people don't really think about usually when they are riding.
People with psychological disabilities; horseback riding and horse interaction is wonderful for people with problems with attachments, sexual abuse survivors, they make an attachment with the horse, they learn to trust, they learn respect and that translates into their real life.
That is what this is all about.
Horseback riding and horses helping people reach out, reaching potentials in their lives they never expected to.